Okay so in this
video I'm going to
go deeper into how
to interpret your RevTrack
data so you can
actually make decisions that
lead to more sales
and more emails. But
first there's one thing
you need to understand.
So your sales pipeline
isn't just made up
of views, it's made
up of different types
of viewers. So cold
viewers are people who
are discovering you for
the first time, warm
viewers are people who
have seen a few
of your videos, they're
kind of curious but
they're maybe not quite
ready to buy, then
hot viewers are people
who feel like you're
talking directly to them
and they're ready to
buy. And here's the
thing, the topics you
choose, the problems you
solve, the stories you
tell, the frameworks you
give, all of those
massively impact how many
of your viewers are
cold, warm or hot
when they hit your
sales page or come
to your call. So
let me give you
an example. So you
might post a broad
video that gets tons
of traffic but because
the audience is so
cold, conversion drops because
those people aren't ready
to buy. But you
could post a video
that got a fraction
of the views, drove
less traffic but the
conversion rate increased so
you got more sales
because the type of
viewer that went there
was warm and hot.
So you might post
a broad video that
gets tons of traffic
but because the type
of viewer that went
there was warmer. So
the best thing about
RevTrack is really trying
to establish what did
we do in our
videos that drove higher
conversion rates because once
we can establish that
we can make every
video optimized to do
the things that get
viewers warming up and
buying rather than just
getting views. Okay so
to give you an
example of how this
works, what I've done
is I've put in
these metrics. So on
the customized column we've
got clicks, call booking,
sales, the revenue generated
clicks from views, sales
from clicks, sales from
views, and sales from
calls. And I'm going
to show you how
different traffic temperatures impact
these numbers. So let's
look at a video
that's got a ton
of views. Let's pick
this one here. So
we've got 348 ,000
views but it generated
$19 ,000. And if
we click on this
one here we can
see that this video
got 35 ,000 views
but generated $100 ,000.
Why? Well it is
because of audience temperature,
the topic description, and
the number of views.
So if I click
on this one here,
I can see that
the problem discussed and
those things that I
just told you. So
it is not a
case that views just
generate more. It has
everything to do with
what you do in
the video and the
temperature of audience you
drive to your offer.
So let's go back
and look at this
one here. 300 ,000
views, 180 people clicked
on my link for
my product, only two
calls were booked, but
those two calls converted.
So what does that
tell us? Well we
can look at these
percentages here. So our
benchmark, if we are
optimizing a video for
a video, we're going
to have a percentage
of people who are
optimizing a video for
sales. We want to
see a 1 -3
% click from views.
Optimizing a video for
sales basically means doing
a strong call to
action for your product
in that video and
you can do it
by stealth selling or
promotional selling. That's a
bit more obvious. So
if I was making
this video specifically to
get more sales, this
would be a flop.
I didn't do a
very good call to
action. So the traffic,
came in, it blew
up to a new
audience, it brought in
cold people and I
didn't promote my offer.
So as a result
we got very few
clicks. But of the
people that did come
in, 1 % converted.
So if we look
at conversion rate of
traffic to a sales
page, especially for a
high ticket offer, that's
not the worst. And
it's not the worst
for a low ticket
either. I certainly wouldn't
say it's a massive
fire.
So you can say,
oh, well of the
people who did came
in, two people really
valued it and bought.
So the sales from
views is too low.
So we haven't got
any data there. And
then we can see
that my call conversion
on these were high.
So what that can
tell us is whatever
I said in this
video resonated so much
with two people, they
were easier to convert.
And that really the
bottleneck here was just
that I didn't do
a strong enough call
to action and get
enough clicks in the
video. If I'd increased
that click -through rate,
0 .05 to 1%,
could have potentially generated
20 % of the
traffic. So we can
see that the sales
from those views are
20 times the sales
from those views. So
can you see how
important this data is,
right? So there, can
you see the problem?
You can fix it.
So let's have a
look on the other
hand. So I'm going
to click on this
metric now, dollar per
view, which for high
ticket is really handy
because it shows you
how much dollars you
made per view. So
this video here, let's
have a look at
it in terms of
views. It's a flop,
but it made $3
.20 per view. What
that is telling me
is the temperature of
the buyer was very
hot by the time
they reached our sales
call, and something I
did in this video
could have very much
likely warmed them up
so that they were
just ready to hand
over their credit card
details. So we look,
we got views 38
clicks again. 0 .3
% click -through rate
is bad. I was
making that video with
the aim of optimizing
getting as many people
to my sales page
as possible, I did
a very bad job
of doing that which
means I need to
look at this and
go right you know
because if I if
I got that to
0 .9 this call
booking could be 3x
because it's three times
more the clicks if
I got three times
more the clicks I
could have maybe made
three times more the
sales so now we
look at is this
next one sales from
clicks so we can
see that 10 %
of the people who
actually clicked bought which
is very high so
this is telling me
that whatever I did
in this video warmed
them up a ton
with the topic and
the content and then
it's saying 200 %
sales from calls now
the reason this might
have happened is because
we had people book
calls after watching another
video then watch this
video and then convert
in between so sometimes
these numbers for call
bookings can be a
little bit off but
what you will find
is often the videos
with the strongest conversions
so let's just go
by sales numbers are
the ones that impress
the viewers and the
ones that impress the
viewers and the ones
that impress the viewers
and the covered a
very specific problem that
they have so this
video here is a
roast where I showed
people how to fix
a problem it's likely
the viewers watching that
well that's the problem
I have I want
them to help me
this one was about
turning viewers into buyers
which is a very
big specific problem my
clients have and then
if we look at
the ones that did
rubbish for sales in
comparison you can see
that 92 ,000 you
know one sale what
was it I did
wrong so the game
of the game isn't
what got the most
views it's coming in
and going what did
I say and do
to get the most
clicks what did I
say and do to
get the most sales
from those clicks what
did I say and
do to convert more
sale calls now if
you have a low
ticket let's just remove
call booking it's the
same thing so we
can look here and
go right let's look
at sales this video
was alive it got
a very strong conversion
rate from the people
who clicked so what
did I say and
do to get the
most sales from those
clicks I say I'm
doing that that warmed
up the traffic this
one here five percent
conversion rate that's great
what did I say
and do in that
video to get this
number that high same
here so that the
most important metrics really
are these two clicks
from views and sales
from the clicks because
these two are telling
us how hot your
audience was when they
entered your funnel if
that's really high and
your views are low
we really need to
do is start getting
more views if your
views are high and
these are low you
have to fix your
offer or work on
your positioning and it's
the same for email
and email marketing and
it's the same for
email marketing and it's
the same for email
marketing so if we
go to a lead
magnet I have let's
change our columns let's
get rid of the
cells let's get rid
of anything other than
email right so we
can now look at
let's have a look
at 12 percent click
from views that's insanely
high look how bad
those views are that's
one of the worst
performing videos I've made
in a long time
on my channel but
this is the best
for email conversion in
terms of metrics right
so if we go
to a lead magnet
I have let's change
our columns let's get
rid of all the
views I've made in
a long time on
my channel but this
is the best for
email conversion in terms
of what we do
is we don't cry
about this not doing
that well we learn
the lesson and go
what was it I
did in that video
but got me this
so that I can
then apply it to
others and the thing
that worked in this
video was this video
was kind of weird
because I didn't actually
do a call to
action for my email
at all I simply
showed off the AI
systems I had built
my clients and there
was a link below
my video that said
click to get my
free AI bot and
people just found it
so there was no
call to action in
that so this could
have been even higher
This one, same. It's
a very high 8
% click from views,
1000 emails, very strong
performance for the views.
What did I do?
Well, I used my
AI tool in this
video and said, you
can get it below.
Guess what? Same thing
in this one. So
we want to be
using these metrics for
email to test different
calls to action, test
different lead magnets and
test different ways of
asking. And if we
can just focus on
the clicks from views
and then the email
signups from views, and
then repeat what these
things, good metrics in
more videos, you'll just
grow your business. So
these columns will tell
you different things. I
don't think I would
have them all on
all of the time.
And other things you
can do is have
this like this. So
you click.
Now we can have
all offers on and
let's say you click
on a video here
and then you can
see all of this
data. But I think
that's too hard. To
interpret, I prefer doing
by video, by email,
by website. And if
I were you, I
would check this data
at least once a
month. And I would
not necessarily look at
the month for videos.
I just, you can
keep looking at all
time because these older
videos will still convert.
But what you'll find
is once you've got
six months of data,
you're going to start
playing a completely different
game to everyone else.